Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 5 years of related experience.

Experience

2022-11 *-* 2023-03

Data Analyst

IAA

- Extracted and interpreted data patterns to translate findings into actionable outcomes.
- Trained images for AI using Microsoft Custom Vision and Form Recognizer, increased detection success rate to 98%
- Managed product backlog and supported Scrum framework for bi-weekly sprint releases.
- Streamlined and optimized workflow and communication by implementing Agile frameworks.

2020-01 -2023-03

Consultant

Sogeti, Westchester, IL

- Supported clients with business analysis, documentation, data modeling, and full stack applications.
- Clients include IAA and Proctor & Gamble
- Created and developed detailed work plans to meet business priorities and deadlines.
- Delivered outstanding service to clients to maintain and extend relationship for future business opportunities.

2022-01 -2022-07

Software Engineer, MuleSoft

KPMG

- Collaborated with the team using Mulesoft Anypoint Studios, XML, and Postman.
- Analyzed APIs through Postman to validate the status code returned 200 which decreased errors by 90%.
- Updated the runtime version of APIs through Mulesoft Anypoint, resulting in 0% downtime for Cloudhub Services.

MICHAEL SAWLANI

Full Stack Developer

Contact

Address

Orlando, FL 32801

Phone

630-418-2211

E-mail

sawlani.michael@yahoo.co m

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-sawlani/

WWW

https://michaelsawlani.com

Skills

CSS proficiency

JavaScript programming

HTML expertise

ASP.Net Core

React

Angular

MongoDB

Node.JS

SQL

Express

RestAPI

• Initiated change requests to elevate important changes to system resources.

2020-12 -2021-02

Full Stack Developer

Proctor & Gamble

- Reviewed code, debugged problems, and corrected issues.
- Development of full stack web application using Next.JS, Bootstrap, and C#.
- Implemented price Spyder allowing customers to purchase products from retailers, which achieved 20% more customer stratification.
- Researched current trends to stay knowledgeable in Scrum methods.

2016-08 -2019-08

Web Developer

MD Pediatric Center, Oak Lawn, IL

- Designed navigation for web pages which allowed for seamless transition using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Oversaw design on appointments by integrating Healow which increased customers by 20%
- Leader in SEO by ranking website top five by utilizing meta tags and keywords

Education

2016-08 -2019-08

Bachelor of Science: Software Development

Full Sail University - Winter Park, FL

Certifications

Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4and Technology

C#

RestfulAPIs

Agile and scrum

API design knowledge

TypeScript